Inventory of the E. B. Brossard papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and writings by Brossard, 1950-2003
  - "Rómulo Betancourt,", 1958 (Box-folder 35: 7)
  - "United States Foreign Relations with Venezuela,", 1967 May (Box-folder 35: 8)
  - "The Venezuelan Agrarian Reform,", 1967 May (Box-folder 35: 9)
  - "A Comparison of Two New British Commonwealth Nations: Barbados and Guyana,", 1967 November (Box-folder 35: 10)
  - "Conosca a Venezuela,", 1974 (Box-folder 35: 11)
  - "Rómulo Betancourt y Fidel Castro,", 1975 April 3 (Box-folder 35: 12)
  - "Coming-Blackouts,", 1978 October (Box-folder 35: 13)
  - Report on California trip, 1983 March (Box-folder 35: 14)
  - "The Global Energy Picture and OPEC,", 1989 October 21 (Box-folder 35: 15)
  - Review of book on Brazilian oil, 1994 (Box-folder 35: 16)
  - "Do Floridians Want Electricity?,", 1998 June 10 (Box-folder 35: 17)
  - "Growing Opposition to Hugo Chávez in Venezuela, and in the Bush Administration,", 2002 February 17 (Box-folder 35: 18)
  - "A Venezuelan March for Liberty,", 2002 May 1 (Box-folder 35: 19)
  - "The Destruction of Petróleos de Venezuela,", 2003 February 15 (Box-folder 35: 20)
  - "Oil Companies Sometimes Help Despots,", 2003 April 30 (Box-folder 35: 21)
  - "Segunda invasión cubana a Venezuela,", 2003 June 15 (Box-folder 35: 22)
  - "Chávez's Brutality against PDVSA,", 2003 September 26 (Box-folder 35: 23)
- Correspondence, 2002-2003
  - Galliano, Ralph, 2002 (Box-folder 35: 24)
  - Bush, George W., 2003 (Box-folder 35: 25)
  - Raymond, Lee, 2003 (Box-folder 35: 26)
- Writings by Brossard, 1988-1995
  - "Can We Afford to Ignore Venezuela?,", 1988 (Box-folder 36: 1)
  - "Report on the Latin American Experience with Nationalization,", 1995 February (Box-folder 36: 2)
  - "Report on Venezuelan Petroleum Nationalization,", 1995 March (Box-folder 36: 3)
- Petróleos de Venezuela, 1977-2004
  - Strategic Associations Unit, 1991-2001 (Box-folder 36: 4)
  - Petrolera Ameriven, 1994-2003 (Box-folder 36: 5)
  - Lagoven, 1995-2002 (Box-folder 36: 6)
  - Maraven, 1992-2001 (Box-folder 36: 7)
  - Sincor, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 36: 8)
  - Orifuels Sinoven, 2003 (Box-folder 36: 9)
  - Bitumenes Orinoco, 1980-2004 (Box-folder 36: 10)
  - Gasoline, 1990-2004 (Box-folder 36: 11)
  - Champlin refinery, 1977-1990 (Box-folder 36: 12)
  - Subsidence and compaction, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 36: 13)
- International oil industry, 1977-2000
  - Historical data, 1977-2000 (Box-folder 36: 14)
  - Foreign direct investment, 1983-1997 (Box-folder 36: 15)
- Latin America, 1958-2004
  - Cuba, 1958-2004 (Box-folder 37: 1)
  - Foreign investment, 1971-2000 (Box-folder 37: 2)
- Venezuela, 1952-2004
  - Introduction by Brossard, "El Libertador,", 1984 (Box-folder 37: 3)
  - Economy, 1974-1986 (Box-folder 37: 4)
  - Guia del consumidor, 1974 (Box-folder 37: 5)
  - Industry, 1971-2000 (Box-folder 37: 6)
  - Public works, 1970-1990 (Box-folder 37: 7)
  - Aluminum, 1986-2001 (Box-folder 37: 8)
  - Cement, 1985-1996 (Box-folder 37: 9)
  - Agrarian reform, 1952-1990 (Box-folder 37: 10)
  - Deforestation, 1995-2003 (Box-folder 37: 11)
  - Visitors, 1971-1994 (Box-folder 37: 12)
  - Venezuelan-American trade, 1984-1995 (Box-folder 37: 13)
  - Culture, 1971-1991 (Box-folder 37: 14)
  - Education, 1971-2000 (Box-folder 37: 15)
  - Trujillo (city), 1960 (Box-folder 37: 16)
  - Venezuelan-American relations, 1971-2002 (Box-folder 37: 17)
  - Foreign relations, 1971-1991 (Box-folder 37: 18)
  - History, 1971-1994 (Box-folder 37: 19)
  - Recall referendum, 2004 (Box-folder 38: 1)
  - Interviews conducted in Venezuela by David A. Rondón, 2003 (Box-folder 38: 2)
- Russian oil oligarchs, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 38: 3)
- Operation Iraqi Freedom, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 38: 4)
- Cuba, 1967-2004 (Box-folder 38: 5)
- Venezuela, 1944-2004
  - Venezuela Up-to-Date, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 39: 1)
  - Petroleum, 1944-2003 (Box-folder 39: 2-9)
  - Petroleum, 1984-1990 (Box-folder 40: 1-2)
  - Citgo, 1986-2004 (Box-folder 40: 3-4)
  - Ley de salvaguarda, 1982 (Box-folder 40: 5)
  - Food imports and prices, 1974-1989 (Box-folder 40: 6)
  - Electricity, 1960-2003 (Box-folder 40: 7)
- Memoir by Brossard, "Emma Brossard's Family and Friends," volume 1, 1995 (Box-folder 40: 8)
- Video recordings, 1991-2004
  - VHS videocassette relating to the international oil industry, 1985 (Box-folder 41: 1)
  - VHS videocassette containing a speech by Brossard, 1991 November 8 (Box-folder 41: 2)
  - VHS videocassettes relating to Venezuela under the presidency of Hugo Chávez, 1999-2004 (Box-folder 41: 3-7)
  - DVD videodisc relating to Venezuela under the presidency of Hugo Chávez, 2004 (Box-folder 41: 8)
- Petroleum industry, 1939-2004
  - History, 1939-2000 (Box-folder 42: 1)
  - Gulf Oil Corporation, 1975-1984 (Box-folder 42: 2)
  - Worldwide reports, 2001-2004 (Box-folder 42: 3)
  - Refineries and production, 1984-2004 (Box-folder 42: 4)
- Venezuela, 1935-2007
  - Angel Falls, 1960 (Box-folder 42: 5)
  - Income tax law, 1991 (Box-folder 42: 6)
  - Oil policy of Rómulo Betancourt, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 42: 7)
  - Historical data on petroleum industry, 1935-1992 (Box-folder 42: 8)
  - Economy, 1970-1985 (Box-folder 42: 9)
  - Articles by Gustavo Coronel, 2003-2007
    - 2003 (Box-folder 43: 1)
    - 2004 (Box-folder 43: 2)
    - 2005 (Box-folder 43: 3)
    - 2006-2007 (Box-folder 43: 4)
- Latin America, 2006 (Box-folder 44: 1)
- Venezuela, 1966-2007
  - Chávez, Hugo, 2004-2007
    - 2004-2005 (Box-folder 44: 2)
    - 2006 (Box-folder 44: 3)
    - 2007 (Box-folder 44: 4)
  - Rosales, Manuel, 2006 (Box-folder 44: 5)
  - Sale of Citgo, 2005 (Box-folder 44: 6)
  - Grupo 400, 2006 (Box-folder 44: 7)
  - Foreign companies and Hugo Chávez, 2003 (Box-folder 45: 1)
  - Empresas mixtas, 2006 (Box-folder 45: 2)
  - Amazonian gas pipeline project, 2006 (Box-folder 45: 3)
  - Petróleos de Venezuela, 1966-2007
    - Deterioration, 2005-2007 (Box-folder 45: 4)
    - Attack on Apertura, 2006 (Box-folder 45: 5)
    - Sale of refinery to Alpha Group, 2004 (Box-folder 45: 6)
    - Internationalization, 1985-2004 (Box-folder 45: 7)
    - Petroamerica and Petrobras, 1995-2004 (Box-folder 45: 8)
    - Sales and supplies to Cuba, 1976-1996 (Box-folder 45: 9)
    - Oil accord with Cuba, 2000-2006 (Box-folder 45: 10)
    - Plataforma Deltana, 2003-2007 (Box-folder 45: 11)
    - Special reports to management, 1966 (Box-folder 45: 12)
- Cuba, 1971-2002
  - Energy accord with Venezuela, 2000-2002 (Box-folder 45: 13)
  - Oil industry, 1971-2007 (Box-folder 45: 14)
- Venezuela, 1971-2007
  - Giusti, Luis, 1997-2006 (Box-folder 46: 1)
  - Oil reversion bill, 1971-1986 (Box-folder 46: 2)
  - Occidental Petroleum Corporation, 1976-1988 (Box-folder 46: 3)
  - Gas industry, 1984-1995 (Box-folder 46: 4-5)
  - Petróleos de Venezuela, 1983-2007
    - Orimulsion, 1983-2006 (Box-folder 46: 6)
    - Corporación Venezolana de Petróleo, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 46: 7)
    - Sosa Pietri, Andrés, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 46: 8)
    - Restructuring, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 46: 9)
    - Appointment of new president, 1990 (Box-folder 46: 10)
    - Board of directors, 1992 (Box-folder 46: 11)
    - Statutes, 1985 (Box-folder 46: 12)
    - Corpovoz articles, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 46: 13)
    - Obituaries, 1986-2007 (Box-folder 46: 14)
    - Law suit, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 46: 15)
    - Finance offering, 1998-2004 (Box-folder 47: 1)
    - Board of directors, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 47: 2-3)
  - Relations with Guyana, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 47: 4)
- Petroleum industry, 1949-2007
  - General, 1949-1998 (Box-folder 47: 5)
  - Guyana, 1977-2007 (Box-folder 47: 6)
  - Suriname and French Guiana, 1975-2004 (Box-folder 47: 7)
  - U.S. oil exports, 1984-2000 (Box-folder 47: 8)
- Address lists, 1992-2006 (Box-folder 47: 9)
- St. Norbert College, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 47: 10)
- Hillsdale College, Center for Constructive Alternatives, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 47: 11)
- Miscellaneous articles, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 47: 12)
- Petroleum industry, 1959-2006
  - American Petroleum Institute meeting, 1986 (Box-folder 48: 1)
  - History, 1976-1006 (Box-folder 48: 2)
  - Data, 1959-2006 (Box-folder 48: 3)
- Venezuela, 1958-2006
  - General, 1960-2006 (Box-folder 48: 4)
  - Caracas, 1958-2006 (Box-folder 48: 5)
  - United Nations Conference on the Law of the Sea, 1974-2004 (Box-folder 48: 6)
  - Grupo Santa Lucía, 1993 (Box-folder 48: 7)
  - National anthem, 2003 (Box-folder 48: 8)
  - Traffic and transportation, 1959-2001 (Box-folder 48: 9)
  - Science, 1981-1995 (Box-folder 48: 10)
  - Junta, 1958 (Box-folder 48: 11)
  - Politics, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 48: 12)
- Puerto Rico, 1976-2006 (Box-folder 48: 13)
- Grenada, 1983-2004 (Box-folder 48: 14)
- Bush, Jeb, 1998-2006 (Box-folder 48: 15)
- Photographs of Ronald Reagan, George Bush, and George W. Bush, 1990-2004 (Box-folder 49: 1)
- Pearl Harbor and World War II, 1991-2007 (Box-folder 49: 2)
- Strauss, Leo, 2003 (Box-folder 49: 3)
- Formal logic, 1948 (Box-folder 49: 4)
- Monograph by Brossard, Power and Petroleum: Venezuela, Cuba and Colombia, a Troika? (2001)
  - Proofs, 2001 (Box-folder 49: 5)
  - Gift copies, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 49: 6)
  - BookMasters Inc., 2001-2002 (Box-folder 49: 7)
  - Amazon.com, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 49: 8)
- Venezuela, 1961-2001
  - Petróleos de Venezuela, 1985-1999
    - Financial statements, 1998 (Box-folder 50: 1)
    - Report on safety, 1998 (Box-folder 50: 2)
    - History, 1985 (Box-folder 50: 3)
    - Annual reports, 1989-1999
      - 1989 (Box-folder 50: 4)
      - 1990 (Box-folder 50: 5)
      - 1991 (Box-folder 50: 6)
      - 1992 (Box-folder 50: 7)
      - 1993 (Box-folder 50: 8)
      - 1994 (Box-folder 50: 9)
      - 1995 (Box-folder 50: 10)
      - 1996 (Box-folder 50: 11)
      - 1997 (Box-folder 50: 12)
      - 1998 (Box-folder 50: 13)
      - 1999 (Box-folder 50: 14)
    - Annual reports of subsidiaries, 1980-1991
      - Corpoven, 1981-1987
        - 1981 (Box-folder 51: 1)
        - 1987 (Box-folder 51: 2)
      - Intevep, 1986 (Box-folder 51: 3)
      - S. A. Meneven, 1982-1984
        - 1982 (Box-folder 51: 4)
        - 1983 (Box-folder 51: 5)
        - 1984 (Box-folder 51: 6)
      - Lagoven, 1980-1991
        - 1980 (Box-folder 51: 7)
        - 1981 (Box-folder 51: 8)
        - 1982 (Box-folder 51: 9)
        - 1983 (Box-folder 51: 10)
        - 1984 (Box-folder 51: 11)
        - 1985 (Box-folder 51: 12)
        - 1986 (Box-folder 51: 13)
        - 1987 (Box-folder 51: 14)
        - 1988 (Box-folder 51: 15)
        - 1989 (Box-folder 51: 16)
        - 1990 (Box-folder 51: 17)
        - 1991 (Box-folder 51: 18)
  - Venezuelan constitutions, 1961-1999 (Box-folder 51: 19)
  - Maps, 1966-2001
    - Venezuela, 1966-2001 (Box-folder 51: 20)
    - Caracas, 1985 (Box-folder 51: 21)
    - Energy resources in Venezuela and Latin America, 1993 (Box-folder 51: 22)
  - Conferences, 1985-1986
    - "Venezuela's Role in World Oil Supplies: Past, Present, and Future," Washington, D.C., 1985 September 13 (Box-folder 52: 1)
    - "Venezuela: Its Importance to U.S. Oil Supplies," New York City, 1986 April 1 (Box-folder 52: 2)
  - Brochures, reports, and serial issues, largely relating to the Venezuelan oil industry, 1980-1997 (Box-folder 52: 3-17)
- History of Standard Oil, 1944-1984 (Box-folder 53: 1-7)
- Ethanol, 2007 (Box-folder 53: 8)
- Oil shale, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 53: 9)
- Strauss, Leo, 1973-2002 (Box-folder 53: 10)
- Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC), 1986-1994 (Box-folder 54: 1)
- Trinidad, 1996 (Box-folder 54: 2)
- French Guiana, 1971-1997 (Box-folder 54: 3)
- PetroCaribe, 2004-2006 (Box-folder 54: 4)
- Venezuela, 1932-2007
  - History of oil industry, 1932-2006 (Box-folder 54: 5)
  - Venezuela Up-to-Date, 1949-1978
    - 1949-1954 (Box-folder 54: 6)
    - 1960-1978 (Box-folder 54: 7)
  - Venezuelan personalities, 1965-2006 (Box-folder 54: 8)
  - Petróleos de Venezuela, 1981-2007
    - PDV America, 1988-2003 (Box-folder 54: 9)
    - Pepex, 2003 (Box-folder 55: 1)
    - Lagoven, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 55: 2)
    - San José Accord, 1980-2007 (Box-folder 55: 3)
  - Visit by Richard Nixon, 1958 (Box-folder 55: 4)
  - Virgen de Coromoto, 1952-1996 (Box-folder 55: 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1957-1995 (Box-folder 55: 6)
- Bronfman, Edgar M. and family, 1984-2006 (Box-folder 55: 7)
- Guyana, 1971-1986 (Box-folder 55: 8)
- Petroleum industry, 1982-2006 (Box-folder 55: 9)
- Denmark and the Basque country, 1974-2003 (Box-folder 55: 10)
- Venezuela, 1951-2000
  - Venezuelan constitution, 1999 (Box-folder 56: 1)
  - Petróleo, 1951 September (Box-folder 56: 2)
  - Petroguía, 1985-1992
    - 1985 (Box-folder 56: 3)
    - 1990 (Box-folder 56: 4)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 56: 5)
  - Petróleos de Venezuela, 1980-2000
    - Corpovoz, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 56: 6)
    - Statistics, 1989 (Box-folder 56: 7)
    - General, 1980-2000 (Box-folder 57: 1-6)
    - Annual reports, 1980-1988
      - 1980 (Box-folder 57: 7)
      - 1981 (Box-folder 57: 8)
      - 1982 (Box-folder 57: 9)
      - 1983 (Box-folder 57: 10)
      - 1984 (Box-folder 57: 11)
      - 1985 (Box-folder 57: 12)
      - 1986 (Box-folder 57: 13)
      - 1987 (Box-folder 57: 14)
      - 1988 (Box-folder 57: 15)
    - Report on meeting with South/West Energy Council, 1989 (Box-folder 58: 1)
    - Centro Internacional de Educación y Desarrollo, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 58: 2-3)
    - Lagoven, 1980-1996 (Box-folder 58: 4-7)
  - Petroleum industry, 1985-1998 (Box-folder 58: 8-10)